Vaia Chouchouli

169, Kanari Street, Petroupoli, Athens, Greece

Mobile:0030 6972330040

E-mail: vchouchouli@gmail.com

PROFILE

A Food Technologist with an MSc in nutrition and public health and 17 years of experience in the food sector. Worked in Laboratory, Quality assurance, Quality control and Quality management departments, with thorough knowledge of food, pet food, food contact materials legislation, international standards, development, implementation, and audit of food safety standards. Highly organized person, open-minded, persistent, restless spirit, always seeking for the best result.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Food Safety Management Systems:

(Development, implementation, audit)

Legislation:

(Food, Pet food, Food contact materials)

Greek legislation

Codex Alimentarius

BfR Recommendations

Laboratory skills: Food microbiology

physico - chemical analyses, ELISA

Sensory evaluations

Computer skills: Microsoft Office & Libre Office (Proficient level)

Predictive microbiology tools,

Languages: Greek (Mother tongue)

English (Proficient level) French (Mediocre) Spanish (Beginner)

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Set up and run an in house food microbiological laboratory which led to the reduction of annual cost analyses
- Contributed to increasing compliance to Food Safety Management System through continuous audits in the food production units, the retail stores and the suppliers of the company.
- Trained the personnel in food safety issues and in the implementation of HACCP plan.
- Set up and run the process of reviewing and collecting documentation relating to legislative and specifications requirements for FCM articles imported from EU and non EU suppliers
- Contributed in the reduction of complaints from Greek Food Safety Authorities regarding
 the Food safety status of the production units and the retail stores of the company and the
 labelling of private label products.
- Developed specification for food, pet food and food contact materials according to legislation and commercial standards.
- Prepared the labelling for the Private Label products.
- Organised the plan for chemical and microbiological analyses in raw materials, final products, pet food, food contact materials and areas, water and processed the data.

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

March 2020 - Now

• Set up and manage the process of reviewing and collecting documentation relating to legislative and specifications requirements for FCM articles imported from EU and non EU suppliers and the packaging materials used in the retail stores and production units.

February 2015 – March 2020: Quality Management Department, Sklavenitis Group

- Worked in the development, implementation and audit of HACCP in the Retail Stores (small, medium and hypermarkets).
- Trained the store supervisors on HACCP and Food safety issues.
- Developed the specifications private label food, pet food and food contact items.
- Organised and run the plan for chemical and microbiological analysis Private label products (food, pet food, FCM) and process the annual data for conducting risk assessment.
- Developed the specifications for disposable gloves (PE, PVC, NRB, LATEX).
- Worked in the recording and the improvement of corporate procedures regarding food safety management.
- Monitored the procedure for the animal by-product handling. Aggregated, analysed and presented the data for each semester.

October 2005 – February 2015: Quality Assurance & Quality Control Department, I & S Sklavenitis

- Worked in the establishment of internal food microbiology laboratory.
- Conducted analysis in raw materials, final private label and branded products and on food contact areas, following ISO protocols.
- Worked in the development, implementation and audit of HACCP and ISO 22000 in the production units of the company (Packaging of dried nuts, spices, cereals and dried legumes, Meat cutting and production of sausages, Production and packaging of ready to eat meals, Restaurants inside the Retail Stores).
- Worked in the development, implementation and audit of HACCP and ISO 22000 in Storage facilities of the company.
- Conducted audits to suppliers.
- Developed the specification for raw materials and final private label products (dried nuts, spices, herbs, meat, cereal, ready to eat meals, confectionary products).
- Monitored the specifications of raw materials (dried nuts, spices, cereals, dried legumes).
- Organised the plan for chemical and microbiological analysis in raw materials and final private label products. Developed an extensive reporting system using spreadsheet program (Microsoft Excel) in order to aggregate, manage and present the data.
- Prepared the labelling of private label products according to EU and Greek legislation (presentation, nutrition declaration, health claims, Quid,etc).

January 2005 – October 2005: Quality Control Department, I & S Sklavenitis – Ice cream and Confectionary Production Unit

- Worked in the development, implementation and audit of HACCP.
- Monitored the production.
- Conducted hygiene controls (measurement of bioluminescence).

September 2003 – December 2003: Internship in the Epidemiological Department, Institut Municipal d 'Investigació Mèdica (IMIM), Barcelona

- Determined the glucose and lipid profile in the blood of participants in the research.
- Determined the oxidative stress biomarkers in blood using ELISA methodology.
- Aggregate and managed the data base for statistical analyses using SPSS program.
- Enhanced my laboratory skills, my knowledge, my computer skills and enjoyed very much working in a multicultural environment.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

2008 – 2012: Harokopio University of Athens, Department of Nutrition and Dietetics MSc Applied nutrition and dietetics – nutrition and public health

Principal subjects:

Nutrition & Metabolism, Food quality and safety, Novel and functional food, Research methods and statistics, Biochemistry

Publication: V.Chouchouli et al(2013). Fortification of yoghurt with grape (vitis vinifera) seed extracts. LWT-Food Science and Technology, 1-8

1999 – 2004: Technological Institution of Athens, Department of Food Technology and Nutrition

BSc Food Technology

Principal subjects:

Food microbiology, Chemistry, Biotechnology, Biochemistry, Food processing, Quality control of meat & meat products, cereals, dairy products, oil and fat, fruit & vegetables, Food packaging, Statistics, Food legislation

Thesis: The preference of European consumers in food

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

Registered trainer at the Hellenic Food Authority (EFET)

INTERESTS

I like travelling, reading, swimming and playing tennis.

REFERENCES

References available on request